Artem Pakhomov

PHP Developer from Kyiv, Ukraine

Phone: +380 (50) 027-93-00 Email: setnemo@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/setnemo

I have been working in the web industry for the past six years. I write a code according to SOLID, KISS, YAGNI, DRY. I publish all my pet projects on github as I adore open source. I am a backend developer and I fancy creating telegram bots. I began studying to play piano during the lockdown. This CV was created on PHP with Github Actions as I can't live without automation.

Technologies

PHP: OOP, SOLID, REST, TDD, PHPDoc, PSR, MVC, Composer, Laravel

DB: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

Tests: PHPUnit, Codeception

Git: unserstand rebase, reflog, squash, cherry-pick, soft/hard reset, etc

Unix: used ArchLinux, Debian, MacOS, vim, grep, sed, ssh, etc

Containers: docker, k8s

Dev environment: nginx/docker, Postman, PHPStorm, xDebug

Experience

PHP Developer at Digitex Kyiv, Ukraine - 04/2021 - Present

- writing code with tests and documentation, working with queues, dockerize services, configure CI, etc
- implemented processes for developers, designers, managers via Jira for a team of 10-20 people. Process has flows for designing, developing, testing and releases

PHP Developer at airSlate Inc Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 04/2021

- · writing code with tests and documentation, code review
- · deploy on dev/rc for testing, deploy release on prod
- create alert rules and checking the cause of alerts, working with metrics (tech and business)
- · duty on burning issues

PHP Developer at Wallet Factory Kyiv, Ukraine - 01/2019 - 05/2019

- Back-end development for a Fin-tech mobile application.
- PHP 7+, OpenSSL, payments API integrations
- API integrations for sales/discounting etc

PHP Developer at MakeTop Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2015 - 12/2018

- Implementation for search engine optimization
- Work with Opencart, Wordpress, etc.

Education

Software Architect UNIT Factory, Kyiv - 09/2017 - 11/2018

I am in the top 5 students of UNIT Factory (course 2017), I completed the 3 year program in 1 year. UNIT Factory StudHub. Volunteering in Exam. Event organization. Meet-up organization.

Pet projects

Repeat Word Bot https://t.me/RepeatWordBot

- Telegram bot to help you repeat new English words and learn pronunciation
- PHP, Doctrine, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

Currencies in UA Bot https://t.me/CurrencyUA_bot

- · Currency conversion inline for Ukraine
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Api integrations, Docker

Asterios RB bot https://github.com/omentes/asterios-bot

- Bot that helps players from Asterios Lineage II Server
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

Begone github.com/setnemo/bygone

- Archive your old repositories to one repo (git history included) with Github Actions
- bash, git, Github Actions

Publications

There King Kashchei withers over gold, or how to save all old repositories into one including git history (RU)

https://habr.com/ru/post/570404/

Archive your old repositories to one repo (git history included) with Github Actions

Introduction to Metrics for PHP Developer (RU)

https://habr.com/ru/post/544582/

The purpose of the article is to acquaint the reader with the principles of working with metrics in php. A ready-made mini-project in docker has been prepared for the article.

Refactoring a pet project: dockerization, metrics, tests (RU)

https://habr.com/ru/post/542978/

The story of how I refactored one of my telegram bots, which from a makeshift turned into a service with more than 1000 users in a very narrow and specific audience.

Languages

English - Elementary proficiency

Russian - Native or bilingual proficiency

Ukrainian - Full professional proficiency

Licenses & certifications

Coursera: C++ Development Fundamentals: White Belt Link

Volunteer experience

SuperGrandchildren at Happy Lunch

CO "Lifelover"

Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 03/2020